<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on CMSC643: Machine Learning and Data Mining</title>
    <link>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on CMSC643: Machine Learning and Data Mining</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Released under the MIT license</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: SNP finding</title>
      <link>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_4/</guid>
      <description>Due: Thursday May 11, 2017
Posted: May 2, 2017
Last Update: May 2, 2017
You will implement approximate string matching using a seed-and-check strategy based on exact matching using the Burrows-Wheeler transform. We are providing starter code to get you going. Instructions on implementation and code are here:
https://gitlab.umiacs.umd.edu/hcorrada/cmsc423_project4
I highly, highly recommend that you use git
To get code you will be using for this project using git:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Gibbs Sampling, EM and evolution</title>
      <link>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_2/</guid>
      <description>Due Monday March 6
Posted: 2/23/2017
Last Update: 2/23/2017
Programming Questions Submit your answers to Problems 4 and 5 in the Rosalind final submission page.
Question 1. (5 pts) Write three or four sentences as a postmortem on the implementation of the two algorithms. What was the biggest challenge in implementing and testing these algorithms?
Note: Postmortem refers to short reviews usually done after completion of a project to set down lessons learned through the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Similar document searching via MinHash and Locality Sensitive Hashing</title>
      <link>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_1/</guid>
      <description>Due: Monday Oct 3, 2017
Posted: Sept. 12, 2017
Last Update: Sept. 18, 2017
In this first project we will implement the system described in the lecture notes for similar document searching. This project is inspired by http://mccormickml.com/2015/06/12/minhash-tutorial-with-python-code/ (Note: you can look at code there for inspiration but implement your own).
The Task We will use documents from this repository http://www.inf.ed.ac.uk/teaching/courses/tts/assessed/assessment3.html. This is a dataset of documents for which we want to find possible plagiarism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Genome Assembly and String Alignment</title>
      <link>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/project_3/</guid>
      <description>Due: Tuesday April 18
Posted: April 4, 2017
Last Update: April 16, 2017
Programming Questions Submit your answers to Problems 6 and 7 in the Rosalind final submission page.
Code Grading (60 pts) Same guidelines as Project 1.
Assembly For this exercise you will use your code for string reconstruction using DeBruijn graphs to analyze genomes from the Ebola virus. Download data for this exercise at this URL:
http://cbcb.umd.edu/~hcorrada/CMSC423/downloads/hw3data.zip</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CMSC643 Projects</title>
      <link>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 08:54:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.hcbravo.org/dscert-mldm/projects/</guid>
      <description> Similar document search with MinHash and LSH  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>